先生 你身上可是沾了不少血啊
You know, you've got a fair amount of blood on you there, sir.
哦
Oh.
对 这都不是我的血
Yeah, it's not even mine.
刚才有个...头号人物
There was just this... number one.
听着 我需要你把这玩意儿拿走
Hey, listen, I need you to take this thing off
别让我再沾手 让别人去处理吧
my hands and just make it someone else's problem.
我本来以为儿子们会喜欢 但...说真的
Yeah, I mean, I thought my boys were gonna love it, but... I'll tell you,
他们绝对受不了
man, they will not.
不 不是玩具
No, it's not.
对 就是个玩具
Yeah, a toy.
所以 永远别这么叫它
So, don't ever call it that.
这是...其实...我也不知道它到底是什么
It's a... it's... actually, I don't know exactly what it is.
而且看起来已经坏了
Besides, it appears to be broken.
看 击鼓棒卡在上升位置了
See, the drumstick seems to be stuck in the up position.
你绝对不想让这该死的鼓棒砸下来
You do not want the goddamn drumstick to come down.
明白吗？
Okay?
因为当它落下时 我保证...
Because when it does, I promise you...
我们全都得完蛋
We are all fucked to hell.
懂吗？
Okay?
好吧
Well,
先生 我不敢代表你 但...我感觉自己还没到完蛋的地步
sir, can't speak for you, but... I don't feel especially fucked to hell.
我不确定每个父亲是否都会把某种隐秘的恐惧传给子女
I don't know if every father passes some secret horror onto his kid.
子女们
kids.
但我父亲确实这么做了
But mine sure did.
我叫哈尔·谢尔伯恩
My name is Hal Shellborn.
这是我和双胞胎哥哥比尔
This is me and my twin brother Bill.
这是变故之前的我们
This is us before everything.
比尔是那种说"击掌为誓" 却突然缩手假装
Bill was the kind of kid that would say shake on it, but then pull his hand back
抹头发耍帅的小孩
and pretend to slick his hair.
他比我早出生三分钟 还霸占了母亲大部分的关爱
It was older than me by three minutes and eight most of my mom's persona.
所以他成了我的"大哥"
So that made him my big brother.
他对此十分较真 一有机会就把我当废物对待
I really took seriously and treated me like a shit whenever he got the chance.
我本不想告诉你
I didn't mean to tell you.
妈妈讨厌你是因为你长得像爸爸 尽管她还得去约会
Mom just hates you because you made dad even though she has to go on dates.
但我还是爱他 即使我偶尔
But I managed to love him anyway, even if I did
幻想过成为独生子
sometimes fantasize about being an only child.
我恨你 比尔·谢尔伯恩
I hate you, Bill Shellborn.
母亲独自抚养我们 直到她再也撑不下去
My mom raised us on her own for as long as she could at least.
关于母亲 我对她的记忆清晰得就像昨天
And my mom, well, I can remember her perfectly like it was yesterday.
你们的父亲
Your father.
他出门买包烟就再也没回来
Well, your father went out for a pack of cigarettes and never came back.
只剩我和这些破铜烂铁作伴
Just me, like an egg and scrap.
我本可以成为他的空乘人员
And sure, sure, I could have been one of his stewardesses,
但这混蛋从没带我去过任何地方
but of course the deadbeat never took me anywhere.
只带回瑞士布谷钟和垃圾饮食指南
Just brought back Swiss cuckoo clocks and bomb dietary.
尼克·诺克斯和些假正经的纪念品
Nick Knox and souvenirs to stuff are plausible.
终有一天 我亲爱的孩子们 这些垃圾都会是你们的
And one day my darling boys, all about horseshit will be yours.
母亲觉得这都是垃圾 但对
We know my mom thought it was a bunch of junk, but for
我和比尔来说 父亲的衣柜里藏满了他的线索
Bill and me, dad's closet was full of clues to who he was.
哦  确实
Oh, she is.
这玩意儿能敲钟
Well, that beats the skies.
巴黎兄弟会还是什么组织的东西？
How's that thing from Paris Frats or something?
写着"街头艺人的猴子像人生"
It says organ grinder monkey like life.
我是说人生像坨屎
I mean, life like dumb shit.
什么？
Oh, what?
嘿  把那东西给我
Hey, give me that thing.
拿去
Here.
你觉得我转这个会响吗？
Do you think this does junk if I turn this?
别弄坏爸爸的
Don't build, dad's.
爸爸早死了 蠢货
Dad's gone, fuck face.
我是他的直系亲属 所以法律上这些都是我的
And I'm his next of skin, so legally, everything in your mind.
反正是个破玩意儿
Stupid things broken, anyway.
别进我们房间 蠢货
Don't come in our room, dumb shit.
我睡上铺
Shotgun.
当然
Obviously.
天 还有什么比相亲更糟？
Christ, what's worse than a blind date.
你亲青蛙时会不会
You're one of their teeth when your hands
担心被它的牙齿划伤？
doesn't kiss a goddamn frog and see what happens.
好了孩子们
Okay, boys.
刷完牙不许喝汽水
No soda after you brush your teeth.
不准玩火
And no fires.
也不准玩电子游戏——因为上次的火灾
And no video games because of the last fire.
我说了别玩火 但这些孩子就是任性
I tried to tell him no fires, but these boys are nothing but willish.
谢谢你 保姆安妮
Thank you, babysitter Annie.
我午夜回来
I'll be on my midnight.
孩子们 今晚只有一卷厕纸
Okay, boys, got only one roll for tonight.
擦屁股时手别碰马桶圈 懂吗？
Keep your hands off the hot parts of the table, okay?
尽量吧...但我是男人啊
I'll try, but... just a man.
哈尔 别闹了
I'll pill, knock it off.
嘿 ！
Hey!
或许这种经历能让我和比尔更亲近
Maybe an experience like that could have brought me in bill closer.
但事实证明 一次诡异悲剧远远不够
But it turned out one freak tragedy wasn't going to be nearly enough.
她的头还完整吗？
I was her head still together.
哦  当然
Oh, yeah.
今天和你对话的是安妮·威尔克斯
Today, you're here with Annie Wilkes.
意外身亡
Gone by accident.
或者说因事故去世——毕竟世上没有意外
Rather in an accident because, you know, there's no accidents.
难道有神圣安排？
Is there a divine plan?
当然 你知道的
Sure, you know.
或许吧
Maybe.
就像抛硬币
Call it a coin toss, you know.
非正即反
No heads or tails.
但安妮的头不算——那是单独事件
But not Annie's head because that is separate.
那是另一回事
That's a separate issue.
知道为什么是她吗？
You know why her?
对吧？
So, right?
为什么是安妮？
Why Annie?
为什么不是你？
Why not you?
或你？
Or you?
万物皆有因
Everything for a reason.
对 没错
Yeah, totally.
存在即合理
And it is what it is.
It is what it is.
主的话语
The word of the Lord.
万物皆偶然
Everything is an accident.
或万物皆必然
Or nothing is an accident.
殊途同归
Either way.
本质相同
Same thing.
重要的不是如果或如何
It's not if or even how.
而是何时
It's only when.
人终有一死
Everybody dies.
所以我会死
And that's why I'll die.
你们也会死
And you will both die.
你们的朋友、他们的父母、所有宠物 所有人
And all of your friends and their parents and all of their pets and everybody.
有人安详离世
Some of us peacefully in our sleep.
有人惨遭横祸——被晾衣绳绞死
And some of us horribly violently died up with clothesline.
嘴上封着胶带尖叫而死之类的
Screaming through duct tape over our mouths and all that jazz.
去他的
And hell with it.
跳舞去吧
Let's go dancing.
我参加过
I've been on
葬礼当天
the day of a funeral.
但那可能是我人生最快乐的一天
But that probably was the happiest day of my life.
世事无常真是讽刺
That's funny how quickly that can change.
嘿
Hey.
小子
Kid.
你哥说你爸抛弃了你们母子
Your brother says your dad left your mom.
去买烟是因为你是个爱哭鬼
Let out to pair his friends.
你整天哭闹害他出门买烟
To buy cigarettes because you're a big fat baby.
你总是哭
You cry all the time.
老兄
And man.
你妈不该过更好的生活吗？
Don't you moms deserve better?
她不该吗？
I mean, don't she?
所以现在你家是你妈说了算？
So I guess that means your mom will be wearing the pants in the house now, huh?
应该是这样吧
I think that's how it works, yeah.
哦  可你现在穿着裤子
Oh, but see, you're wearing pants.
一个家不能同时有两个人掌权
And two people can't be wearing the pants in the house at the same time.
看来你家有点权力矛盾啊 小子
So looks like you got yourself a bit of a pants problem, kid.
宝贝 我在做花生酱果酱三明治
Honey, I'm making PB&J.
等等
Oh, wait.
我该怎么应付这两个儿子一整天？
How am I going over my two sons all day long?
为什么不把爸爸的猴子放我们房间？
Why don't you put dad's wear and monkey in our room?
自从发现那只臭袜子我就不进他房间了
You know I don't go in there anymore since I found that step sock.
哦  这样啊
Oh, yeah.
保姆的头和你无关吧？
You didn't have anything to do with my babysitter's head right?
那也太扯了
That'd be like, yo.
你真的很迷那玩意儿？
You really got the hots for that thing, huh?
我没有
I don't.
没事
It's all good.
可以给你 但你要说想和它结婚
You can have it, but I got to do say you want to marry.
我不想和你结婚
I don't want to marry you.
说"我想当蠢猴子夫人"
Say, I want to be Mrs. Stupid Monkey.
我想当蠢猴子夫人
I want to be Mrs. Stupid Monkey.
我还要说...
I'll say...
我想吸它的香蕉
I want to suck it's banana.
不要 菲尔
No, Phil.
不
No.
不说我就吃掉你的胎盘 混蛋
Say it or I'll eat the rest of your placenta, bitch.
我想吸它的香蕉
I want to suck it's banana.
成交
All right.
猴子归你了
You have a deal.
你拿走猴子
You can have the monkey.
吃
Eat
下去
it.
哟 托伦斯太太
Yo, Mrs. Torrance.
她居然容忍他在课桌下玩猴子
How she opens, joking his monkey under his desk.
你在
You're
做魔鬼蛋糕
making devil's food.
老子才不要
I don't fucking want any.
谁这么和母亲说话？
Who talks to their mother like that?
你想说什么？
What do you want to say?
我算什么东西？
What kind of shit am I?
你
You.
都怪你让比尔住进我身体
It's because of you that that be built in this to me.
知道我在说什么吧？
You know what I'm talking about, don't you?
那个和我共生的混蛋？
That asshole kid who lives in here with me?
那是比尔
That's Bill.
想知道别的吗？
You want to know something else?
我希望比尔死掉
I wish Bill was dead.
妈你回来了
Hey mom, you're home.
晚餐没好吗？
Is that not ready?
妈
Mom.
不 你还没做好
No, you've been making it yet.
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck?
医生说我妈得的是回旋动脉瘤
The doctors call what happened to my mama, boomerang aneurysm.
但只有我知道真相
But I was the only one who knew what it really was.
他们说发病概率是四千四百万分之一
They said chances of it happening were one in 44 million.
换个说法就是——
And that's just another way to say.
总得有人中招
It has to happen to somebody.
这就是规则
And that's how it works.
你转动发条 鼓棒升起
You turn the key and the drumsticks go up.
当它选定下个目标时就会落下
They come down again when it chooses who wants to kill next.
不接受点杀
It doesn't take requests.
想杀谁就杀谁 想何时杀就何时杀
It kills who it wants when it feels like it.
无需解释
And it doesn't owe you an explanation.
盒子上说得对
It's true what it says on the box.
就像人生
It's just like life.
儿子 也许最好...
Son, perhaps it's best.
闭嘴
Shut up.
妈
Hey mom.
妈 醒醒
Mom, wake up.
妈？
Mom?
妈 这玩笑不好笑
Mom, that's a funny joke.
妈
Mom.
你
You
知道你的姑父奇普
know your anidone, your uncle chip.
从不想要孩子
Never wanted kids.
对
No.
他就喜欢整天瘫在椅子上
Always just kind of prefer to life where you sit
想起来才动一动
down and you don't stand up again until you want to.
我们还是换妻爱好者呢
Also, we're swingers, but oh well.
我们会尽力照顾你们兄弟
I want you to know we're going to do our very best with you boys.
虽然这个"尽力"可能很糟糕
It's just that our very best might be pretty bad.
见鬼？
The fuck?
我把碎片装进垃圾袋确保被收走 以为这事就了结了
I put the pieces in a garbage bag and made sure it got on the garbage truck and I
以为就此结束
assume that would be the end of it.
从此我和比尔形同陌路
After that, Bill and I were never the same.
长相当然一样——毕竟是双胞胎...你懂我意思
I mean, we looked the same because we were twins and... You know what I mean?
艾达姑妈和奇普姑父带我们搬去缅因州
And Ida and Uncle Chip picked up Bill and me and moved us to Maine.
本以为能把噩梦留在过去
And I guess I hope we'd left the worst of it behind us.
他们说万物皆可替代
They say everything and be replaced.
他们说天涯若比邻
They say every distance is not near.
而我记得所有细节
So I remember everything.
我要脱掉你的西装 比尔
I'm going to take off your suit, Bill.
脱掉后下次葬礼还得再穿
If I take it off and I'll have to put it back on as soon as there's another funeral.
不脱就不用再穿——
Or if I don't take it off then I won't have to put it back on.
这样就不会再有葬礼
So there won't be any more funerals.
睡个好觉
Sleep tight, you two.
为什么带它来？
Why'd you bring it?
我没有
I didn't.
我明明剁碎了
I chopped it up.
看着可不像碎块
Don't look chopped up to me.
听着比尔
I'm telling you, Bill.
它是只坏猴子
It's a bad monkey.
它是只坏猴子 杀人的坏猴子
It's a bad, bad, killer monkey.
我猜是它杀了保姆安妮
I think he killed babysitter Annie.
也许？
Maybe?
可能吧 不确定
Probably, I don't know.
我本来要娶她的
I was going to marry that girl.
我知道你会 比尔
I know you would, Bill.
我们该故意试试看会不会死人
We should try it on purpose to see if anyone else we know dies.
不不不
No, no, we shouldn't.
万一选中我们呢？
I mean, what if we get to one of us?
那我发誓会假装为你哀悼
Then I promised her pretend to be sad when you're dead.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
转动发条的人会被杀吗？
You think you could kill the person who turns the key or not?
鬼知道
How the hell should I know?
你觉得是妈妈转的吗？
Do you think Mom turned it?
我要试试
I'm going to try it.
别 比尔
Don't, Bill.
奇普姑父死于猎奇事故——
It was a hunting accident, but not the usual kind.
野营时在睡袋里被67匹
Uncle Chip was trampled by a stampede of 67
野马群踩踏致死
wild horses in a sleeping bag on a camping trip.
殡仪员说尸体倒出来时
I overheard the undertakers say that when they dumped the body
像被踢爆的樱桃派
out, it looked like someone had dropped kick to cherry pie.
我倒不介意奇普死了
I don't mind what the Uncle Chip's gone.
他本来就是个混蛋
It was kind of an asshole.
只是庆幸死的不是我
I just mind more that I feel pretty good wasn't me.
但总得有人处理这事
But it's got to be done, you know?
免得落到居心叵测的人手里
To keep it away from the people who might feel really good about using it.
纳粹、俄国佬那些混蛋
The Nazis and Russians and our wrong keys and whatnot.
既然毁不掉 就只能封存
We knew that it couldn't be destroyed, so we hoped that we could maybe contain it.
彻底摆脱它
Just get rid of it.
让这鬼东西滚远点
And make it go to fuck away.
很长一段时间里 似乎成功了
And for a long time, anyway, it really seemed like it had.
自从把它扔进井里再没见过
I haven't seen the monkey since we threw it down the well.
但感觉它迟早会回来
But it feels like only a matter of time before it comes back.
这是如今的我
This is me today.
基本和比尔断了联系 这样挺好
I'm pretty much lost all contact with Bill, and I'm good with that.
反正他也是个混蛋
He was kind of an asshole, anyway.
没朋友 刻意疏远家人——
I don't have any friends, and I do my best to stay away from family.
怕猴子回来伤害亲近的人
For fear that if the monkey returns, I don't kill someone close to me.
但疏远家人谈何容易
But staying away from family, that's easier said than done.
嘿 德怀特
Hey, Dwight.
哦 伙计
Oh, man.
快进来
Come in, come in.
不用 我得走了
Oh, no, it's cool.
今天要早点接孩子
I got to run early today.
接我儿子
I got to pick up my kid.
等等 你都有孩子了？
Wait, you got a kid?
真够惨的
Shit, man, that sucks.
长得像你吗？
Does it look with you?
我知道
I know.
不像
No, he doesn't.
一年见一次 今天带他去恐怖乐园
But I get seen once a year, so I'm taking him to a horror heaven.
其实是过山车乐园
Well, the coasters, I guess.
一年才一次？太惨了
Once a year, shit, man, that sucks.
前妻是个母夜叉吧？
I bet you expect some type of megabitch, huh?
不 一年一次是我的主意
Oh, no, the once a year thing that was my idea.
毕竟我是个坏榜样
It turns out I'm kind of a bad influence.
麻烦来了
Here comes trouble.
你是？
Who you?
倒不是说我见过苍白马和苍白骑士
It's not like, you know, I've beheld a pale horse, and on it was a pale writer,
骑士名叫死亡...
and the writer's name was, you know, death.
不过确实经历过类似的事
But, yeah, that has been some of the other.
真够惨的
Shit, man, that sucks.
的
Of
我们的租赁能量转移给你了
our rental energy transferred from you to me.
彼得最近总问起你
Peter's been asking about you more and more how.
让人心碎
Man, it's breaking our hearts.
问我？
About me?
问我什么？
What about me?
什么？
What?
学校要做家谱 你毕竟是
Because your his father, and he's doing a family tree
他血缘上的分支
school project, and like or not, you're one of the branches.
听着 我在乎彼得
Look, I care about Peter.
真的
I do.
非常在乎
I care about him a lot.
特别在乎
Like, a lot.
刚才在沙发上 我吸走了你的能量
Just now, when we were on the couch together, I took your power.
我允许你吸了吗？
Well, well, well, well, I never said you could take my power.
这不重要了
It doesn't matter anymore.
泰德要正式收养彼得
But Ted has decided to legally adopt Peter.
什么？
What?
收养完成后你就
And once the adoption is finalized, it won't
不用再见他了
be necessary for you to see Peter at all.
你们不能这样！
But you can't just do that.
不能！
You can't just do that.
我可是这行的权威专家
That's the leading expert in my field.
我不能吗？
Can't I?
你们父子还有一周时间
Listen, you and Peter have this time.
创造点美好回忆然后彻底了断
So just take the week, lock in some nice memories, and then cleanly cut it off.
像切除退化尾巴
Like a vestigial tail.
这不正是你想要的？
That's what you want, isn't it?
不是
No.
这不是我要的
It's not what I want.
我想陪彼得
I want to spend time with Peter.
你知道退化就是...
It's just, you know, a vestigial.
指失去功能的器官
It means something that has become functionless.
没有存在必要的东西
And as a result, there's no longer necessary.
我知道意思 泰德
I know what it means, Ted.
你当然知道
I'm sure you do.
我知道
I do.
我吸了你的能量
Well, I have your power.
彼得想要门口的灌木...
So, well, like, Peter wanted your bushes on the way in.
现在该我提议...
So... Now, this is the part where I suggest that we... I miss all.
赌什么？
I miss all for what?
赌上全部
For all the marbles.
用你的蛋蛋当筹码
And by marbles, I am of course referring to your little balls.
我的...
My...
亲爱的
Honey.
哦 彼得
Oh, Peter.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
你们在聊什么？
What are you guys talking about?
这让你想起你父亲？
It mean it reminds you of your dad.
是指那猥琐笑容还是背上痦子？
You're talking about the shitting grin or the hairy back-and-ons.
想过他在哪吗？
Did you ever wonder where he is?
我是说你爸
Oh, dad, I mean.
宝贝 不值得费心
Baby, that ain't worth it.
硬要说的话——
But if you're really looking for an answer, I'd have
不是在赌桌就是在妓女肚皮上
to go with either at a card table or under a hooker.
对
Yes.
马克 注意言辞
Mark, come on, I have a cross.
两种说法都成立
It both sounds honey.
想抽一口吗？
If you want a drag.
你还要把猴子卖给
But you're still thinking of selling that monkey
那个死宅怪咖？
thing to the nut who never leaves his house.
从没当面交易过
I'm gonna be ever even met this guy face-to-face.
听着就是个变态
Sounds like a real fucking pervert to me.
你有兄弟姐妹吗？
So, do you have any brothers or sisters?
这是你的家谱作业？
Is that your family treating?
我要交作业
I'll give it away.
好吧
Okay.
所以 有兄弟姐妹吗？
So, brothers, sisters?
算有也算没有
Yes, no.
哦 不
Oh, no.
不 两种状态都有
No, it's a both.
算有也没有
Yeah, no, neither.
这么说吧
Let me tell.
和我一样
Just like me.
你妈妈叫什么？
What's your mom's name?
洛伊丝
Lois.
你妈妈叫...
Your mom's name is...
我要迟到了
I'm gonna get a late time.
让她给你弄点吃的？
She'll get you some dinner, huh?
想活命的话
Oh, if you want me to like survive.
当然
Yeah.
酷
Cool.
都这么干
Everybody did it.
天
Christ.
喂？
Hello.
怎么找到我的 比尔？
How did you know I didn't reach me, Bill?
五年没联系
I haven't heard from you in about five years.
十年没见面
I haven't seen you in like ten.
警察怎么回事？
What do you mean the police?
必须处理
I have to.
情况紧急
It's like that.
没时间了
It's no more.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
她年纪大了
I guess she was kind of old.
生病了？
Was she sick or something?
实际上老太太在...
Well, actually it seems the old girl was having someone.
然后呢？
Okay, and what?
需要亲属处理遗物 你是继承人
Someone has to go through her belongings and you're in the next of kin.
严格说比尔才是继承人
Technically, you're the next of kin, Bill.
这周凯蒂归我 不行
And this is my week with Katie, so no.
你真怂
You're weak.
你就这点能耐陪儿子
That's all you get with your son.
再说你真怂
Also, you're weak.
你到底要怎样 比尔？
What do you want, Bill?
去遗物房确认猴子不在那里
Go to an item house and make sure it isn't there.
它在井底待着呢
It is at the bottom of a well.
它会瞬移还会附身
It can teleport and you interchange.
天
Jesus.
怎么会去遗物房？
Why would it be at an item is anyway?
它缠上我们家族专杀血亲
Because it attaches itself to our family and likes to kill us.
我不想死在牢里
I don't want to die in prison.
你也不想我死对吧？
You don't want me to die either.
我能怎么办？
What am I supposed to do?
从飞机上扔下去啊！
Drop it from a fucking plane.
估计会弹回来
You're probably bounce.
不 你必须时刻盯着它
No, you've never let it out of your sight again.
防止有人转动发条
So no one turns the key.
你总不想凯蒂停止谈论凯蒂吧？
I'm presumably you don't want Katie to stop talking about Katie.
必须消灭猴子
The monkey must be vanquished.
你怎么不去？
Why don't you van?
比尔在哪？
Where's Bill?
你体格小
You're smaller.
你去
You go.
比尔！
Bill.
等等等等等等！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
凯蒂
Katie.
快走
We got to go.
赶紧走
怎么回事？
What's going on?
搞什么？
What the fuck?
注意言辞
Hey, language.
必须马上走
And we got to go.
好吧
All right.
他们就在外面
They were there.
外面有东西
There was a thing outside.
不是东西
It wasn't a thing.
是那个
It was one.
不管怎样必须撤
And either way, we got to split.
好吧
All right.
快走啊
So come on, let's go.
现在大半夜的
It's the middle of the night.
你嗑药了？
Are you high?
没
No.
我倒希望！
I wish Jesus Christ.
不 我不碰毒品
No, I don't do drugs.
认真的
I mean it.
快点
Come on.
赶紧
Let's go.
快点！
Hurry up.
我要睡觉
I'm going to bed.
我们是你家人
We're your mate.
嘿 凯蒂
Hey, Katie.
刚才抱歉
Sorry about that.
我饮食不规律
It's just my entire diet.
要处理家族遗留问题
I've got to deal with a lot of our stuff.
能问个问题吗？
Can I ask you a question?
我注意到你从没提过
I'm really aware that he didn't.
你妈妈怎么死的？
How'd your mom die?
家谱作业需要 通常
Just for your family tree thing, because usually
家谱都记录活人
family trees are about to lose in the wind.
不过我家不太吉利
It's not that wise in the house.
是姑妈抚养你长大的？
Was your aunt the one that raised you after your mom died?
对
Yeah.
是的
没错
Yeah, she did.
或许你能带我去看看老宅
Maybe you could take me to your own house with you.
我帮你整理遗物
I can help you with your stuff.
你不能带宝宝去
And you cannot come over with my baby.
为啥？
Why not?
那里太压抑
Because it's depressing.
好吧
All right.
本来说好去游乐园
We're supposed to go to a theme park.
不是去接触黑暗与死亡
Not into, you know, darkness and death.
我知道领养的事
I know about the adoption home.
哦
Oh.
你可以直接切断联系
And so you can either just cut me off and cut this off.
或者珍惜剩下的
Or you can spend the rest of it.
每一分每一秒
Every little time that we have left together.
我在想
I wonder
如果降低标准会怎样
if one lowers what he chosen.
一个人躲这儿干嘛？
What are you doing in here all alone now?
别问不想知道的
Where do I not want to know?
随便想想
Just thinking, I guess.
是吗
Oh, yeah.
想什么？
About what?
不知道
I don't know.
未来吧
The future.
你把我难住了
You got me in vice.
保护好牙齿
Well, take care of your teeth.
注意肠胃
And take care of your gut.
顺其自然
Take life as it comes.
别强求任何事
You know, the worst thing you can do is try to force it.
但最重要的是记住...
But really, I think that the most important thing for you to remember is...
别杀光身边的人
Try not to kill everybody around you.
啊！
Aah!
小豆
Beanie.
准备好了？
Ready?
嘿 小豆
Hey, Beanie, buddy.
看这个
Check it out.
镇上有家店
There's a place in town.
教口技表演
They'd just try nothin' lessons.
感觉这是你擅长的
I feel like it's one of those things.
我们以前很擅长
We were really good at it.
而你不是
And you aren't.
我想去听听课
I want to come and listen to find out.
嘿 有意思
Hey, funny.
真有意思
That's funny.
是啊
Yeah.
我们以前也挺逗吧？
We were kind of funny too, huh?
他们还承办婚礼
Oh, and they do weddings.
嘿 对
Hey, yeah.
帮我个忙
We're doing me a favor.
好的
All right.
我们在车里
We're in the car.
我只需要处理...
All I deal with is...
什么？
What?
不行
No way.
我想看你旧房间
I want to see your old room.
电影里都这么演
Let me do it in the movies.
别闹
No, Beanie.
你就要
You want to.
因为...我说了算
Just because... Because I said so.
好吧
All right.
行
Fine.
那我要拉屎
Then I have to go number two.
什么？
What?
去汽车旅馆拉
Why don't you go to the motel?
你对我了解太少了
There's a lot you don't know about me how.
比如我只在房子里拉得出屎
For instance, I'm one of those kids that can only go poo in a house.
真是输给你了
Everything's serious.
这赌局太狠了
That's a tough bet to lose how.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
嘿
Hey.
你好
Hey there.
抱歉
Sorry.
我要摔下去了
Oh, I know I'm going to go down.
你好
Hey there.
你好吗？
How are you?
我是芭芭拉
I'm Barbara.
你一定是哈尔·谢尔本
You must be Hal Shelborn.
你哥比尔说你今天会来
Your brother Bill Shelborn said you'd be coming.
哦 对
Oh, yeah.
是的
Right, right.
你好芭芭拉
Hi Barbara.
你哥比尔真是个活宝对吧？
That brother Bill of yours is quite the character, isn't he?
是啊
Yeah.
你哥比尔啊
Your brother Bill, I mean.
对的对的
Yes, yes.
确实是个活宝
He's quite the character.
是啊
Yeah.
这小家伙是谁？
Wow, who's this little slugger?
这是我儿子皮特
Oh, this is my son Petey.
你好呀
Oh, hello there.
不用客气芭芭拉
Oh, no thanks Barbara.
我只是个不常买房的小孩
I'm just a kid who doesn't buy many houses.
而且我都不知道有个叔叔
But I also didn't know that I have an uncle.
所以
So, yeah.
多谢提醒
Thanks for that.
有趣的是我昨天问他有没有兄弟
It's funny because I actually asked Hal here if he had no siblings yesterday.
他当面撒谎
But he flat out lied to my face.
不过没关系
But it's cool.
反正他当我爸也就几天了
He's only gonna be my dad for like a few more days anyway.
马上要换成权威专家了
Because he's being swapped out for a leading expert.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
好的
Yeah.
行
Okay.
那么
Well.
没名片
So no card.
对
Okay.
不用名片
No card, yeah.
你和姑妈很亲吗？
Were you and your aunt very close?
当然
Sure.
就这些遗物？
Is this all her stuff?
感觉她东西更多啊
I feel like she had more stuff.
我们办过遗产拍卖会
Oh, well, we did have that estate sale that day after she died.
来的人可多了
We had a great turnout too.
赚了上百美元呢
Must have made over a hundred dollars.
好吧
Right.
让我看看
Now, let's see.
周日处理的
That would have been on Sunday.
周一开始这里就乱套了
Because ever since Monday, things have been a bit messy around here.
你姑妈周一去世的
Yeah, your aunt, of course, was Monday.
周二轮到米奇·麦克唐纳
And then, oh Lord, first thing Tuesday, it was Mitch McDonald's.
周三伯特·伯格森
And then Wednesday was Bert Bergerson.
接着南希·瑞索利
And then Nancy Risoli.
有眼镜蛇拌蛋黄酱吗？
Any cobras and mayonnaise, are there?
有过一起
Well, there was the one.
自周一起每天至少死一个本地人
No, every day since Monday, at least one casco local has just poof.
有时两三个甚至四五个
Sometimes two, or three, or four, or even five, casco locals have just poof
接连暴毙
and poof and poof.
明白了
Great, yeah.
好吧
Yeah, no.
懂了
I get it.
能看看另一个柜子吗？
Can we look at the other closet?
是这里吗？
Is this where I think?
当然
Absolutely.
跟我来
Follow me.
噗
Poof.
你们是双胞胎？
Your fucking twins?
我妈常说每次有空难或校车坠河
No, my mother used to always say whenever there was a plane crash, or a school bus
这种群体性死亡事件
going off into the river and mass fatalities, or what have you.
她总说"上帝在玩宾果游戏"
She used to always say, looks like God's bullying strikes tonight.
哦 奇怪
Oh, that's odd.
我记得没锁啊
I don't remember locking this.
你当然不用记这些
Yeah, you wouldn't have to remember if my
如果我姑妈有发条猴子的话
aunt had a wind-up toy monkey at the archer.
应该没有
No, I don't think so.
看来不是美好童年回忆啊
Oh, not a cherished childhood memory now, was it?
毛茸茸的玩伴充满奇思妙想？
Oh, first little furry friend filled with whimsy and wonder.
不存在的
No, it is.
没啥特别的
No, no big deal.
好吧
Oh, okay.
不是这个
Nope, not that one.
钥匙好用吗？
How are we doing that key?
别担心
Oh, don't you worry.
你这漂亮脑袋
You're pretty little head.
玛茜我说出声了吗？
Oh, Marcy, did I say that out loud?
小心
Watch out.
你确实漂亮
You are pretty, though.
知道吗？
You know what?
我们该用排除法
I actually think we should go down.
逐步排查可能性
We should go down a little process of elimination.
不不不不！
No, no, no, no!
都检查完了？
Is everything abandoned?
是的
Yeah, everything's fine.
你当时就站着没动手？
And you were just standing there, hands to yourself.
对吗？
Is that right?
对
Yeah, that's right.
知道屋里有枪吗？
And do you know there was a gun in the house or not so much?
不知道
No.
现在要请你
I'm going to have to ask you.
在调查期间不要离开镇子
Don't leave town until we can figure a few things out.
别啊警官
No, no, no, officer.
我答应儿子去恐怖乐园
I promised my son that I was going to take him to horror heaven.
其实警官
I'm actually officer.
我们改去恐怖乐园了
We moved off going to horror heaven.
显然这事更重要
This is obviously far more important.
聪明孩子
Smart kid.
找家汽车旅馆
Find a motel.
这房子现在没法住人
I'd say stay here, but it's a goddamn mess in there.
你上去看过吗？
I mean, have you actually been up there?
简直像
It's like that restaurant.
意大利面灾难现场
Spaghetti city.
是啊
Yeah.
孩子想回车里去吗？
Hey bud, you want to win the car?
你最喜欢让我干这个对吧？
That's your favorite thing for me to do anyway, isn't it?
离远点
Just stay away.
我能不能
Am I able to.
听着我们没事但猴子不在这
Yeah, look, we're fine, but the mucky's not here.
被卖到二手市场了
And I had to have a goddamn yard sale, so it could
现在可能在任何地方
have been, but now it could be
这可不太妙
Well, that's not good.
糟透了
That's bad.
是啊 镇上发生了一堆破事儿
Yeah, it was all kind of shit happening in town.
有人以不正常的方式死去
People dying in not normal ways.
千万别告诉我我不能离开
Please don't mean I can't leave.
去汽车旅馆
Go to a motel.
我会等我的信号
I'll wait my signal.
去等你他妈的信号！
Oh, wait your fucking signal!
等等比尔 你在哪儿？
Wait, Bill, where are you?
比尔 你住在镇上吗？
Bill, are you living in town?
声之诞生
Sound born.
不
No.
猴子女士？
Mrs. Monkey?
这是
This
关于我脑袋的事
is in regards to my head.
很高兴报告会结束了
I'm happy the report key is over.
感谢你到场 路上注意安全
Thank you for going, and be safe out there.
这是
It's
我指尖滑落的时刻
my moment to use slip from my fingers.
我突然知晓了所有可怕的真相
I suddenly knew the terrible truths about everything.
我那蠢货弟弟拧动了你的钥匙 害死了我妈
That my dumb shit brother had turned your key and killed my mom.
我立刻回去找你 可你已消失无踪
So I went back to get you as soon as I could, but you were gone.
只给我留下一丝征兆 暗示终将归来
Leaving behind a sign for me and only me, that one day you'd be back.
于是我等待
And so I waited.
漫长岁月里 空无回响
And for the longest time, there was nothing.
百分百医用级虚无
A hundred percent pure medical grade, nothingness.
直到你出现
There you were.
就像
Just
试炼日月星辰
to test the sun, the moon and the stars.
仿佛你始终在俯视我
As if you had always been looking down on me.
让我知晓自己渴望的真相
Letting me know what I had always wanted to be true.
你会归来助我复仇
That you'd come back to help me seek my revenge.
我重返你可能存在的每个角落
I returned to the places where I thought you might be
愚蠢地相信能让你重现
foolishly believing that I could make you appear again.
以为这次我能找到你
That it was I who might find you again.
于是我为你归来做好准备
So I made myself ready for your turn.
穿上儿时的丧服 准备参加更多葬礼
We're working my old childhood funeral suit in anticipation of, well, more funerals.
只为再次见证你可怖的荣光
And so that I'd like once again, bear witness to your terrible glory.
我寻至苍白之马的居所
So I looked in the home of a pale horse.
其名为死亡
And his name that sat on him was death.
这是我的钥匙
This is my key.
如今我们在此相遇
And now here we are.
终将完成最后的使命
Together at last, with only one thing left to do.
总之 无穷智慧
Anyhow, infinite wisdom.
我信任你 正义之火剑
I trust you, flaming sword of righteousness.
我将斩断污浊 惩戒罪人
I'll cut the foul air, and smite the right person.
你心知肚明我在说什么
And I know you know exactly what I'm talking about.
打扰了 他们烂透了
Excuse me, they're sucks.
什么？
What?
怎么了？
What is it?
我忙得要死
I'm extremely busy.
希望你别介意 我想用15美元换回
Well, I hope this isn't weird, but I was wondering, maybe I could give
那只发条猴子玩具
you your 15 bucks back and instead I could just keep the toy monkey thing.
那不是玩具 别这么叫它
It's not a toy, don't ever call it that.
思考会让你痛苦吗瑞奇？
Does it hurt very much when you think Ricky?
这个嘛 我想...
Well, I thought well, well...
你知道27%的英语使用者临死前会说
Did you know that 27% of all English-speaking people will either say,
"该死"或"天啊"吗？
oh shit, or holy shit before they die?
有趣的是死亡是唯一必然之事
Now it's funny, because death is the one big thing that'll happen to all of us.
但人们总避而不谈
And yet we still can't help but be.
说得好啊老兄
Right on, man.
总之不是...
So anyway, it's not...
它长得像你 但那个...
It looks like you, but that's like, uh...
要是皮蒂拧了钥匙呢？
What if Peteie turned the key?
能还给我吗？
So, could I have it back?
休想
Never.
我要找到猴子 但不会爱上它
I'm going to find the monkey not to fall in love with it.
不！你欠我的 工厂混蛋！
No, you owe me you're the factory!
你自找的！
You're most yours!
有备用子弹吗？
You got any extra bullets?
什么口径？
What caliber?
芭芭拉的子弹你还留着吧
Yeah, you still got some of Barbara's loadin' you.
对
Yeah.
意外总会发生
That accident's happen.
能问个问题吗？
Can I ask you a question?
不能
Nope.
你杀过人吗？
You ever killed him?
好吧
All right.
天啊
Jesus.
这妈妈 不是吧？
This mom, no?
不 没事
No, all right.
我从没杀过人
I haven't killed anybody.
当然没杀过人
Of course, I haven't killed anybody.
听着 回旅馆后我会联系
Look, when we get back to the motel, I'm going to call
你妈告诉她经过
your mom, and I'm going to tell her what happened.
如果你觉得我恶心...随你便
If you don't think I'm not sick to be around, then... You should be right.
所以泰德要说什么？
So, Ted, what just to tell me?
你再也不用见到我
You'll never have to see me again.
你最好有泰德的消息 懂吗？
You better have a Ted, all right?
相信我
Believe me.
看里面
Look in there.
嘿 皮特
Hey, Pete.
需要时我就在这儿
Well, I'm here if you need me.
在浴室做你的事好吗？
You just do your thing in the bathroom, okay?
好 才怪
Yeah, not.
想谈心就好好谈 行吗？
If you want to have a talk, we can have a proper talk, all right?
是
Yes.
是我
It's me.
你还没动手
You haven't done it.
我知道 宝贝
I know, baby.
拜托比尔
Come on, Bill.
这不是我们需要的
This isn't what we need.
我知道你会解决
I know you'll have it.
我算什么？
What am I?
别拧钥匙了
Stop turning the teeth.
这该死的胳膊不够长
These arms aren't fucking long enough for articulate
总得有人来拧
enough to reach back there itself, so somebody has to.
而且不行
And also, no.
他妈的见鬼
Jesus fucking Christ.
比尔 这些人无辜
Bill, these are innocent people.
听着 我不在乎自己
Look, I don't care about me.
只要PDF文件安全
All that matters is the PDF safe.
别拧钥匙了
So stop turning it.
想让我停手？
You want me to stop turning the key?
让皮蒂来接手
Bring pity to me so he can turn it in instead.
什么？
What?
不 为什么？
No, why?
拧钥匙的人不会死
The person who turns the key never dies.
所以现在该让孩子接手
You know, that's where the kids have to do now.
什么？
What?
你在胡说什么？
What are you talking about?
你在哪儿比尔？
Where are you, Bill?
想让皮蒂安全 就得让他不断拧钥匙
If you want pity to be safe, all pity has to do is turn the key and keep turning the
永远拧下去 他就永不会死
key forever and never and never and pity will never die.
听我说比尔
Listen to me, Bill, all right.
让我带皮蒂离开
Let me get pity out of here.
再商量对策
Then we'll talk.
好 我们会想办法
All right, we will figure out what we're going to do.
要么我继续拧 要么皮蒂接手
Either I keep turning the key or pity turns the key.
决定后联系我
We'll call me back when you made your decision.
等等比尔！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, Bill.
嘿 皮蒂 皮蒂
Hey, pity, pity.
嘿 皮蒂
Hey, pity.
皮蒂
伙计我们得走了
Hey, buddy, we got to go, all right.
送你回你妈那儿
I got to take you back to your mom's.
皮蒂开门
pity, open the door.
快点
Come on.
皮蒂
pity.
皮蒂开门啊
pity, open the door.
赶紧 现在就走
Come on, we got to go right now.
老天
Jesus Christ.
我心脏病要犯了
I'll have a heart attack.
或者直接死
Or do.
这么想摆脱我 倒有个捷径
You want out of my life so bad it might just be a nice shortcut.
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck?
为什么不开门？
Why didn't you answer the door?
既然要疏远我
Why would you even have a kid if all you're
当初何必生我？
going to do is just keep yourself away from me?
那时我不知所措
I didn't exactly know what I was doing.
听着 我当时也就是个愚蠢的孩子
All right, I was just a stupid, dumb kid.
所以我是意外？
So I was an accident?
你是这意思吗？
Is that what you were saying?
人生充满意外
Everything is an accident.
对
Yes.
好女人
Well, nice woman.
真欣慰
Great to hear.
这不好笑
That's not funny.
是意外 皮蒂
Yes, it was an accident, pity.
但你不是错误
But you're not a mistake.
很高兴你在我身边
I'm so glad you're here with me.
你对我而言是很珍贵的
You're very precious to me.
我疏远你是因背负着家族诅咒
That's why I stay away because I come with all sorts of weird baggage.
不想让你承受这些
And I don't want you to have to deal with that.
比如什么？
Like what?
糟糕的事 皮蒂
Like bad stuff, pity.
邪恶的东西
Like evil stuff.
从我爸那里继承的 不想传给你
Stuff that I got from my dad and I don't want to pass it on to you.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
比如什么？
Like what?
比如...
Like...
他妈的 警察 开门！
Open up to the motherfucking police!
好 好 知道了
All right, all right, all right, got it.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
冷静
Relax.
冷静点
Just relax.
拿钥匙
Get the keys.
快！
Come on!
好好好知道了
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
不能开车走
We can't go for a little drive.
就停这儿
All right, stop here.
这是哪儿？
Where are we?
嗯？
Huh?
我们在哪？
Where are we?
你兄弟家？
What's your brother's house?
堡垒在哪？
Where's fortress?
别装不知道这是哪
Don't pretend like you don't know where we are.
我真不知道 我们...
I don't know, all right, we're...
我们关系不好
You know, we're estranged.
靠 真惨
Shit, man, that sucks.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
好吧
Okay.
你...进去
You... You go inside.
和你叔叔搞好关系
You make nice with your uncle.
拿到猴子带出来
You get me the monkey and you bring it out.
好
Okay.
什么猴子？
What monkey?
穿红马甲拿鼓的
It's got a little red vest.
我需要它
And it holds a drum and I need it.
这人为什么执着猴子？
What is this guy now about a monkey?
我不懂
And I don't.
他不知道猴子的事 不能进去
He doesn't know about the monkey and he's not going in there.
就是玩具猴
It's a toy monkey.
别这么叫它
Don't call it that, all right?
那不是玩具
It's not.
是邪物
It's evil.
简直就是恶魔
It's basically the devil, all right?
就是个玩具猴
It's a toy monkey.
本想等你长大再说
I was gonna tell you when you were older.
好吧
Okay.
你因为玩具猴当了混账老爸？
You've been a god damn deadbeat dad because of a toy monkey.
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck?
注意言辞
Hey, language.
所以必须远离这里
And yes, but that's why we have to get as far away from this place as possible.
你最好拿到该死的猴子 不然我毙了这货
You got to hope that you get that god damn monkey because I'm gonna shoot this guy.
让我和他一起...
All right, just let me...
让我陪他进去
Let me go in there with him.
不行！
No!
后院有狗洞
There is a doggy door around back and you're
希望这小子够瘦能钻进去
kid better hope that he's scrawny enough to fit.
别报警别耍花样
You don't call the cops or do anything.
进去
You get in there.
拿猴子出来
You get me the monkey.
不然把你们射成筛子
Or I swear I'm gonna shoot you both a lot of times.
他不能进去
He's not going in there.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
好吧
All right.
快去
Go.
该死
Hell.
这太疯狂了
This is some fucked up shit.
我知道
I know.
记住无论如何
It's whatever you do.
别拧猴子背后的钥匙
Don't turn the key in the monkey's back.
知道了
Okay, okay.
操
Fuck.
呃
Huh.
挺酷的
They're kinda cool.
算是吧
I guess.
你真是警察对吧？
You know, really a cop, right?
闭嘴
Shut up.
当然不是
Of course not.
我恨条子
I hate cops.
我爸以前是警察
And my dad was a cop.
现在还是
Still is.
反正据我所知
For all I know.
我妈说他总在外面鬼混
You know, my mom said he was out chasing pussy, but
我就说镇上也有的玩啊
I'm all like there's pussy here in town, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
无所谓
Whatever.
他还是走了
He left.
所以我才恨条子
And that's why I hate cops.
不过咱俩现在也算条子对吧？
We're also the cops, you know?
她才是恨条子的最佳理由
She's the best reason to hate cops.
这玩意儿怎么会在这儿？
What the hell is that doing there?
好吧 你的新娘们呢？
All right, what were your brides?
用我的新娘们敲它就行
Hit it with my brides, okay.
呕 恶心
Oh, gross.
关掉它
Shut it off.
快关掉
关掉！
Shut it off.
我在切了 天啊
I'm cutting it off, Jesus.
我正想做完我的龙卷风
I'm trying to finish my twister.
我可真矫情
I'm so pretentious.
我们将涤荡污浊 精准惩戒罪人
We'll cut the foul air and strike the right person and only the right person.
哦  比尔？
Oh, Bill?
彼得 真是意外惊喜
Peter, what a nice surprise.
你还好吗？
You okay?
告诉我
Tell me.
嗯
Yeah.
你
You.
好久没人这么问我了
There's been a lot of times since anyone's asked me that.
不过你可以提
And I'll let you mention it.
不
No.
我没事
I'm okay.
这是我童年最爱的玩具
There's my favorite toy from childhood.
本来应该打鼓的 可能卡住了
It's supposed to play the drums, but I think it's stuck.
能帮我修好吗？
Would you fix it for me?
现在是你祖父的了
It was your grandfather's now.
他旅行时带回来的
He brought it home from one of his trips.
他是飞行员
He was a pilot.
他是个可怜人
He was a pity-till.
你知道吗？
Did you know it?
我不确定它要告诉我什么
I don't know if it tells me anything.
他当然不知道
Of course he doesn't.
所以就是这个了？
So this is it, then, huh?
他们大多不是为此而来？
The thing that most of them were not?
不 很好
No, good.
不过是个玩具
It's just a toy.
何不试试拧动它？
Why don't you try turning it?
我们需要不同的手法
Well, we just need a different touch.
是啊
Yeah.
转动钥匙只是仪式的一部分
Turning the key is just simply something to show.
祖祖辈辈都在做这件事
More men have been doing for generations.
算是家族传统吧
A tradition, if you will.
若你不愿继承 也不必勉强
But if it's not for you, then it's not for you.
它有什么用？
What does it do?
转动钥匙
Turn the key.
看看会发生什么
See what happened.
要我退后吗？
You want me to back up?
你他妈在晃
You're fucking moving.
你没事
You're okay.
起作用了吗？
Is it working?
我有顶蠢警帽
I had a stupid cop hat.
太疯狂了...
It's crazy, it's...
什么？
What?
我他妈要疯了！
I'm getting so fucking Christ!
手枪用得顺手吗？
How's we going with that pistol, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
相当顺手
Totally.
是啊 很棒
Yeah, great.
该死
Oh shit.
操！
Fuck!
嘿
Hey.
立刻转动钥匙
Turn the key right now.
什么？
What?
不
No.
马上把该死的猴子交出来
They give me the fucking monkey right now.
我可没在跟你商量
I'm not asking myself anymore.
动手
Do it.
杀了他
Kill him.
别怂啊兄弟！
Don't shit, brother!
不知道！
Don't know!
很好
Good.
过来
Come here.
正面硬刚啊
Fight the goddamn front.
天啊
God.
去他妈的
Fuck it.
我勉强不了你
I can't make you.
算了
Fuck it.
真该死！
God damn it!
天！
God!
我他妈的太强了
I'm just so goddamn strong.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 皮蒂
Hey, pity.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
感谢上帝
I thank God.
快点
Come on.
天啊！
God!
该死！
Damn it!
天！
God!
真实
Real.
鼓槌上还刻着皮蒂
The drumsticks still have pity.
妈的 我烂透了
Hell, I'm shit.
这种时候你只会说这个？
That's all you can say at a time like this.
你这混蛋
You fucker.
别废话
Don't shit.
操
Fuck.
去你的
Fuck you.
不过老天在上
Jesus Christ, though.
你真想杀了我对吧？
You're really trying to kill me, would you?
当然
Of course it was.
搞这么大阵仗就为这个
That's what all this carnage was for.
差点杀了皮蒂
Could have killed a peaty.
差点杀了我儿子
Could have killed my fucking son.
从没怎样？
Never what?
为什么？
Why?
因为你杀了我妈
Because you killed my mom.
我知道你想杀我
I know you wanted to kill me.
但死神可不接订单
But the goddamn name doesn't take requests, obviously.
我一直在拧钥匙
I've been turning the keys.
你占有了我的人生
You had my everyday's.
听着比尔
Listen, Bill.
不是我的错
It's not my fault.
也不是任何人的错
I wasn't anybody's fault.
我们不该遭受这些
Not as deserved what happened to us.
只是刚好在场而已
Just happened to be there when it did.
妈妈？
Mommy?
对不起 比尔
I'm sorry, Bill.
但我要走了
But I guess I gotta go now.
人终有一死
Everybody dies.
这就是人生
And that's life.
你妈妈的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry your mom died.
真他妈操蛋
Fuckin' sucks.
我知道你的感受
I know you're feeling.
她也是我妈
She was my mom too.
哦 对
Oh yeah.
确实
I guess you are.
从没这么想过
Never thought about it like that.
可能是个错误
And it's a mistake I guess.
当然
Sure.
不过有道理
Makes sense though.
我们是兄弟更是双胞胎
We're brothers and twins.
对吧？
Right?
对不起
I'm sorry.
真希望孩子们在时我们能互相扶持
I wish we could have been there for each other when my kids.
但现在我们在这
When we're here now.
当你说不的时候
When you say no.
再做兄弟
Brothers again.
当然
Sure.
对不起
I'm sorry.
所以你们想来场公路旅行？
So why'd you two wanna some kind of road trip or something?
是啊
Yeah.
父子公路之旅
I'm gonna... Father's son road trip.
对吧？
Right?
我本可以做点什么
I would like to have done anything.
哪怕一次也好
Somebody at least once.
所以跟我们走吧
So come with us.
所以比尔叔叔的事...等你长大再告诉你吧
So Uncle Bill pretty much... I'd have to tell when you grew up huh?
嗯
Yeah.
你知道我觉得大家都会死
You know I get to have everybody dies.
这就是人生
I mean that's life.
但这次是集体暴毙
But this is like everybody dies.
你知道同时发生吗？
You know what at the same time?
所以...
So...
现在想做什么？
What do you wanna do now?
得想想怎么处理这猴子
I guess we gotta figure out what we're gonna do with monkey.
贴身保管
We keep it close.
接受它是我们的宿命 牢牢守住
We accept that it's ours and we hold on tight.
嘿  我知道现在该做什么了
Hey, I just got an idea of what we should do right now.
去跳舞吧
Let's go dancing.
跳舞？
Dancing?
对啊
Yeah.
用身体跳？
Like with our bodies?
那根棍子哪来的？
Where did that stick come from?
你祖母的遗物
Counts from your grandmother.
我在你身后
I'm below us.
酷
Cool.
确实酷
Yeah that's cool.
Encoded by Spyro